Guide to the Philip Will, Jr. papers, 1941-1985.
Will, Philip, Jr. papers, 1941-1985.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Philip Will, Jr. papers, 1941-1985.
3749
Philip Will, Jr., 1906-
8.1 cubic ft., 1 volume.
Correspondence, speeches, reports, plans, photographs, and other records.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes records of Will's involvement with the American Institute of Architects, including his term as president; his files as trustee of Cornell University, ca.1962-1976, including material concerning the Buildings and Properties Committee; plans for Sigma Phi fraternity at Cornell; and correspondence, speeches, and reports pertaining to the College of Architecture, Art and Planning and to architectural education in general. Also, speeches and photographs relating to Will's nomination for the American Institute of Architects' Gold Medal, 1970.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Philip Will Jr. is a member of the American Institute of Architects, and a trustee of Cornell University. Cornell University Class of 1928. Member, International Fraternity of Lambda Alpha, Ely Chapter.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes records of Will's involvement with the American Institute of Architects, including his term as president; his files as trustee of Cornell University, ca.1962-1976, including material concerning the Buildings and Properties Committee; plans for Sigma Phi fraternity at Cornell; and correspondence, speeches, and reports pertaining to the College of Architecture, Art and Planning and to architectural education in general. Also, speeches and photographs relating to Will's nomination for the American Institute of Architects' Gold Medal, 1970.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Will, Philip, Jr., 1906-; American Institute of Architects.; Cornell University--Buildings.; Cornell University. Board of Trustees.; Cornell University. College of Architecture, Art and Planning.; Sigma Phi.
Subjects:
Architecture.; Architecture--Study and teaching.; Architects.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
Part of Lambda Alpha Literary Archives.
CONTAINER LIST
- American Institute of Architects (AIA) Review Committee, 1959- (Box 1)
- AIA committee files, 1956-1959 (Box 1-2)
- CU Campus Planning (CU Trustee File) (Box 2)
- Speeches (Box 3)
- Trustee Files, especially Buildings and Properties (P. Will became Trustee Emeritus in 1973), 1962-1976 (Box 3)
- Will's material as AIA President (Box 3)
- AIA material, 1951-1977 (Box 4-5)
- Sigma Phi fraternity material and copy negatives, 1927 (Box 6)
- AIA material, 1951-1961 (Box 6)
- Perkins & Will material, includes Project Cost Data volumes, 1963-1970 (Box 7)
- "The Billet Will," family holiday newsletters, 1976-1984 (Box 7)
- Large scrapbook, 1960-1962 (Volume 1)
- 4 sheets of plans for Sigma Phi fraternity house created from photos and appraisals, Apr. 1979 (Mapcase-folder 1)
- Cornell, 1973-1980 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Comprehensive policies - planning and design, 1972-1983 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Cornell, 1983-1985 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Cornell - Pooled Life Income Fund, 1970-1983 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- College of Architecture, 1977-1981 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- College of Architecture Assembly, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 6-7)
- Arch. Ed., 1960-1976 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Cornell Archives, 1978-1984 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Cornell Archives, 1971-1978 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Arch. Ed., 1980-1983 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Arch. Ed., 1960-1976 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Arch. Ed., 1979 (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Arch. Ed., 1978 (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Arch. Ed., 1977-1978 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Arch. Ed., 1969-1984 (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Interviews and miscellaneous writings, 1948-1962 (Box 8, Folder 17-18)
- Excerpts from speeches, 1952-1972 (Box 8, Folder 19)
- Post AIA speeches, 1961-1978 (Box 8, Folder 20-21)
- AIA politics - getting elected, 1956-1961 (Box 8, Folder 22-23)
- AIA speeches, 1952-1962 (Box 8, Folder 24-25)
- AIA fan mail, 1957-1968 (Box 8, Folder 26-27)
- Nomination of Philip Will, Jr. for the Gold Medal, American Institute of Architects, 1970 (Box 9)
- AIA Gold Medal nomination - speech excerpts, 1970 (Box 9)
- AIA Gold Medal nomination - photographs (Box 9)